Contact

singhsaumyas150@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ saumya1singh (LinkedIn) saumyasingh1.github.io/Saumya-Singh/ (Personal) medium.com/@singhsaumyas150 (Blog)

singhsaumyas150.wixsite.com/saumyacodes (Personal)

Top Skills

Android Development
Software Development
Android Studio

Certifications

Winner

Java for beginners

Programming Course

Excellent performance CBSE

Backend Developer Intern

Honors-Awards

Winner

Winner

Women In Open Source Academic Award 2020 finalist by RedHat

Featured Mentor for Google Code In by AnitaB organization

Featured Mentor by AnitaB organization

Saumya Singh

RedHat Open Source Award finalist| Google Connect Winner| SIH Winner| Mentor @GCI @GSSoC @KOSS, IIT| GHCI Scholar New Delhi

Summary

Saumya Singh is a final year student [2017- 2021]. She is a full stack android developer and a member of Google Actions Developer Community. For her Open Source Contributions, she has been honoured as finalist for RedHat's Open Source Academic Award 2020. She has mentored students at Google's open source event Google Code In with Systers and Mifos organisation. She also guided open source enthusiasts for GSoC at KWOC'19 (IIT-Kharagpur Initiative).

Saumya has been part of Developer Advocate and Content Creator team at AnitaB.org Open Source Community.

She has volunteered at Systers Organisation, GirlScript Summer Of Code, Women Who Code - Delhi.

She has been winner & runner-up of 5+ hackathons from Smart India Hackathon 2019(India's Biggest Hackathon that involves 2 Lakh+ students) to Delhi Police Hackathon 2019.

https://github.com/SaumyaSingh1 https://twitter.com/Saumya1Singh

https://saumyasingh1.github.io/Saumya-Singh/#

Experience

AnitaB.org

Developer Advocate [Open Source Teams] at AnitaB.org Open Source May 2020 - July 2020 (3 months)

Intrepid geeks Android Developer May 2020 - June 2020 (2 months)

Google Play
Launched Scan India App, an alternative to CamScanner
Page 1 of 4

May 2020 - May 2020 (1 month)

It took 3 days to build the PDF Scanner app that scans and convert documents into PDFs in seconds. The app is free of ads and it generate scanned PDF in seconds.

We will add more features in updated versions.

Link- https://www.codersgram.com/2020/07/ScanIndia-App.html

Coding Blocks

Teaching Assistant Intern for Android Development Course January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Preparing Quizes, Assignments for the students and writing technical blogs on Android development. Involved in taking up doubts of students.

Google

Google Code In Mentor, 2019 November 2019 - May 2020 (7 months)

GirlScript Summer of Code

5 months

Project Mentor

February 2020 - April 2020 (3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Organizer's Team

December 2019 - April 2020 (5 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Smart India Hackathon 2019

Winner

February 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Kerala, India

GirlScript Foundation

Project Lead Intern

March 2020 - March 2020 (1 month)

New Delhi, Delhi

I am been chosen as project Lead by GirlScript Foundation(https://www.girlscript.tech/) for a project whose motto is "Skill Development for Slums".

GirlScript along in collaboration with cry.org is aiming to make this project a big success by shaping the career of 21 scholar students of the Shahbad SLUM area in Delhi, India.

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur Mentor December 2019 - January 2020 (2 months) India

Mentored students on Software Development Project in Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur initiative for Open Source named KOSS(Kharagpur open source society).

Google Developers Actions On Google 2019 - January 2020 (1 year)

I published A Google Action on Java Interview Quiz and that has been approved by Google.

There are 45 short java questions (along with answers).

Try it on your phone's Google Assistant using this link: https://assistant.google.com/services/a/uid/00000b9e9002eb5?hl=en&source=web

Reviews will be highly appreciated. And that will help me to improve my work on Google too .

Salesforce
Salesforce Administrator Training
September 2019 - October 2019 (2 months)
New Delhi Area, India

Completed Online Training on SalesForce Platform .

HackerRank
Practitioner
2018 - September 2019 (1 year)

EazyPG
Android Developer
July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)
Delhi Technological University, New Delhi

Worked on a project which aims to make PGs of India smart . It is best Indian PG app for owners and tenants. It has 1K + downloads on Playstore . #Android #Firebase

Backstage Supporters
Android Developer at Backstage Supporter
May 2019 - June 2019 (2 months)

Education

Ch. Brahm Prakash Govt. Engineering College
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Information Technology · (2017 - 2021)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Information Technology · (2017 - 2021)

Kendriya Vidyalaya High School| 10th Class · (2015 - 2015)